<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Exploratory Steps :: Data Gators</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/tutorials/exploratory/index.html</link>
    <description>Below are some simple tutorials to follow where you will learn general data exploration. What is data exploration, you ask?&#xA;​ Data exploration is the process of analyzing raw data to find patterns, characteristics, and relationships. It’s the first step in the data analysis process. Why is data exploration important?</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>© Data Gators</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 25 Nov 2024 13:09:06 -0500</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/tutorials/exploratory/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Exploratory Steps With Synthetic Data</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/tutorials/exploratory/intro_synthetic/index.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 25 Nov 2024 13:09:06 -0500</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/tutorials/exploratory/intro_synthetic/index.html</guid>
      <description>Lesson: Introduction to R Programming and Data Science Overview In this lesson, we will introduce you to R programming by loading a synthetic dataset, performing basic correlations, and visualizing the data with several plots. After each code block, we’ll explain how the code works step by step.&#xA;Prerequisites Before we begin, make sure that you have R installed. You can download R from CRAN and use RStudio as an IDE to write and execute R code.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Exploratory Steps with Penguins Data</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/tutorials/exploratory/intro_penguins/index.html</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 24 Nov 2024 03:14:28 -0500</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/tutorials/exploratory/intro_penguins/index.html</guid>
      <description>Introduction to R Programming with the Penguin Dataset Let’s work with the penguins dataset, which contains data about three species of penguins in the Palmer Archipelago, Antarctica. The dataset includes measurements for:&#xA;Bill length (in mm) Bill depth (in mm) Flipper length (in mm) Body mass (in grams) Species (species of the penguin) We will perform basic exploratory data analysis (EDA) by calculating correlations and creating visualizations to better understand the relationships between these variables.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Exploratory Steps With Iris Data</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/tutorials/exploratory/intro_iris/index.html</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 24 Nov 2024 03:03:29 -0500</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/tutorials/exploratory/intro_iris/index.html</guid>
      <description>Introduction to R Programming with the Iris Dataset Let’s work with the built-in iris dataset, which contains data on 150 different species of iris flowers. Each entry contains the following measurements for the flowers:&#xA;Sepal length Sepal width Petal length Petal width Species We will go through the steps of loading the dataset, calculating basic correlations, and creating visualizations to explore the relationships between the different features.&#xA;Step 1: Load the Iris Dataset In R, you don’t need to load the iris dataset manually because it is built-in. We can directly access it.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Exploratory Steps With MPG Data</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/tutorials/exploratory/intro_mpg/index.html</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 24 Nov 2024 03:03:29 -0500</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/tutorials/exploratory/intro_mpg/index.html</guid>
      <description>Let’s explore the mpg dataset from the ggplot2 package in R. This lesson will cover how to load the dataset, calculate basic correlations, and create various plots, with detailed explanations for each step.&#xA;Introduction to R Programming with the MPG Dataset In this lesson, we will work with the mpg dataset, which is included in the ggplot2 package. The dataset contains information about the fuel efficiency (miles per gallon) of various car models, with additional details about each car such as:</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>