<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Lessons :: Data Gators</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/lessons/index.html</link>
    <description>​ Welcome to Data Gators Lessons This section of the site contains a series of lessons designed to help students and faculty at Allegheny College navigate the complexities of computational research. Whether you’re new to data science or looking for guidance on advanced techniques, these lessons will provide hands-on tutorials and step-by-step guides to support your learning.&#xA;What You’ll Learn The lessons cover a range of topics to assist with data analysis and computational tasks, including:</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>© Data Gators</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 02 Feb 2025 03:03:29 -0500</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/lessons/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Lesson 1</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/lessons/lesson_1/index.html</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 02 Feb 2025 03:03:29 -0500</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/lessons/lesson_1/index.html</guid>
      <description>Data Cleaning and Visualization in R 📘 Overview Data cleaning is a crucial first step in any data analysis project. It is estimated that 80% of a data scientist’s work involves data preparation, with around 60% of that time dedicated to cleaning and organizing data.&#xA;In this lesson, we will use the nycflights13::flights dataset to learn practical data cleaning and visualization techniques. This dataset contains over 300,000 flights departing from New York City in 2013.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Data Pre-processing with Iris Dataset</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/lessons/lesson_01_preprocessing/index.html</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 24 Nov 2024 03:03:29 -0500</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/lessons/lesson_01_preprocessing/index.html</guid>
      <description>Introduction to Pre-Processing data in R with the Iris Dataset Let’s work with the built-in iris dataset, which contains data on 150 different species of iris flowers. Each entry contains the following measurements for the flowers:&#xA;Sepal length Sepal width Petal length Petal width Species We will break down the basic steps that make up loading, viewing, and cleaning up the dataset. At the end, we will see the benefit and importance of having a clean dataset, and how failing to adequately do so can cause issues with our analyses.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>